# João Scheleder Neto

## **Electronic Technician**



- me@scheleder.com
- +55 41 99124-8571
- Rua Antônio Czocher, 90, Colombo, Paraná
- Brazilian
- B driver's license
- **15/02/1972**

### Education

Graduate ( Systems
Analysis - Computer
Sciences)

Estácio de Sá University Jan 2014 - Dec 2017

 Technician (Robotics, Industrial Automation and Mechatronics)

SENAI Jan 2011 - Dec 2013

Technician (Eletronics)

Instituto Monitor Jan 2005 - Dec 2009

# Languages

Portuguese

English

#### Links

Portfolio Linkedin Github Facebook

## Summary

I have many years of experience as an Electronic Technician, in industrial automation, installation and maintenance of electrical and electronics equipment and industrial computers. And also good knowledge of communications networks. I have experience with technical and quality standards, interpretation of electronic diagrams and schematics, negotiation with costumers and suppliers, management maintenance contracts, product development and electronic projects.

I'm passionate about what I do and learning new things, dedicated, always try to my tasks on time, obstinate to improve process and I like to share my knowledge and help others. I'm non-smoker and available for travels.

My English level is basic, I understand almost everything I read, but I still have to improve my listening and speaking. I'm working on it.

## Work Experience

# Electronic Technician, Berry Global, São José dos Pinhais PR

April 2018 - June 2022

Responsible for maintenance of industrial computers, backups of system images, improvement and monitoring of the machine vision systems (ISRA) infrastructure. Also working on Industrial automation, maintaining production lines, performing interventions in PLC, inverters, sensors, etc.

#### System Technician, Sicpa do Brasil, Curitiba PR

October 2011 - March 2017

Maintenance of the SICOBE Project, PLC Programming (Beckhoff), repair of printers (desk jets), inverters, servers, vision systems (Cognex and Basler), configuration of sensors and TCP/IP networks. In the last year I was the technical manager of the maintenance laboratory and I also reviewed work instructions and provided technical support to other Field technicians.

\*SICOBE is a governmental control system that tracks the production of beverages throughout Brazil, counting, identifying and printing a datamatrix code on the product.

#### Electronic Technician, previously, Curitiba PR

January 1988 - July 2011

I worked with energy systems (UPS, stabilizers, converters, etc.) for many years, and during this period I had my own business for six years. I have also worked with the development of electronic equipment, automation of granges, reform of electronic scoreboard in the Jockey Club, manufacture of laboratory products and language teaching cabinets.